herbalifeww.com 2014-10-29

# Herbalife - United States - Privacy Policy

Herbalife International of America, Inc. and its U.S. affiliate entities comply with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. As a sign of its commitment to provide a high level of protection for the personally-identifiable information it collects and uses, Herbalife International of America, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Herbalife International of America, Inc.'s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you as to what information may be collected from you when you visit our website ("the Site") or when you become an Independent Herbalife Member or Herbalife customer, how such information will be used by Herbalife and/or other persons or entities, with whom such information may be shared, your choices regarding the collection, use and distribution of such information, your ability to edit, update, correct or delete such information and the security procedures that we have implemented to protect your privacy.

 **NOTICE**

 **Collection of Information**

At different occasions you may be asked for certain types of personally-identifiable information (e.g., your first and last name, mailing address, city, state, zip code, telephone number, email address, credit card number, bank information in connection with automatic deposit/debits, etc.). We hope you will provide us with this information. However, if you do not want to disclose your personally-identifiable information to us, please do not submit it. This does mean that in some cases we will not be able to provide you the service you have requested.

We may also collect non-personally identifiable information from you when you visit the Site (e.g., your IP address, browser type, domain name, etc.). This information is collected and analyzed in the aggregate in order to improve the function and content of the Site.

 **Use of Information**

We use the information that is collected about you for a variety of purposes. You will be informed about these purposes at the time of collection. In general, however, we foresee the following uses:

 **Website visitors**

Information about you may be used to add you to our email subscription list, provide your name to Independent Herbalife Members in connection with your expressed interest in our products or business opportunity, analyze trends and statistics, enhance the operation of the Site, serve content and advertisements and send informational and promotional materials about Herbalife and other companies.

**Customers**

Information about customers will in addition be used to provide customer service, confirm and fulfill your orders, ship your orders, and administer payments and possible problems and disputes with dispatchers and other service providers.

**Members**

Information about Independent Herbalife Members will in addition be used to provide Member services, calculate earnings and bonuses, provide training on new products and services, and ensure compliance with the Application and Agreement of Membership and the company's rules and regulations.

 **CHOICE**

We have existing business relationships and may develop other relationships in the future with business partners. In these instances, we may share or otherwise allow access to information that is collected about you that will enable our business partners to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest. 

At the time we collect your information you will be given the choice to accept or refuse the disclosure of your information for such marketing purposes, and for marketing by Herbalife.

 **ONWARD TRANSFERS**

We may employ vendors to perform functions on our behalf. Examples of such functions include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, email administrative functions, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These vendors are under a contractual obligation to use confidential data received from Herbalife only for purposes that fall within the functions for which they were hired.

We may disclose information that we collect about you when we have reason to believe that this is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities who may be harming you, us or others. We may also disclose information when we believe the law requires it.

Lineage Reports, which contain information on other Members in a Memnber's downline, including, but not limited to, name, address, identification number, telephone number, email address, fax number, level or rank, volume and sales statistics, are provided to Members in the strictest confidence and for the sole purpose of supporting the Members to further develop their Herbalife businesses. (The downline organization consists of all Members that were personally sponsored by a particular Member, and in turn, all other persons sponsored by those Members.)

Lineage Reports, including all data contained therein, constitute confidential, proprietary trade secrets of Herbalife. Members may not collect, distribute or gather confidential information or personal or aggregate information about other Independent Herbalife Members or their customers, except in connection with their downlines and solely for the purposes of promoting their Herbalife businesses, and to manage, motivate and train their downlines.

You need to be aware that Independent Herbalife Members who receive the Lineage Reports may be based in countries that do not offer the same or a similar level of privacy protection as is available in your own country. However, Herbalife will take reasonable measures to ensure that the information is kept in confidence.

 **SECURITY**

We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we collect about you remains accurate, timely and secure. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure and while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee or warrant its complete security. We shall not be responsible for harm that you or any person may suffer as a result of a breach of confidentiality in respect to your use of the Site or any information you transmit to the Site.

 **DATA INTEGRITY**

Personally-identifiable information will be kept in active files or systems as long as needed to meet the purposes for which it was collected or as required to perform the contractual relationship with the Independent Herbalife Member and his/her up-line, and the commercial relationship with the customer.

Herbalife will make reasonable efforts to ensure that the information is accurate and complete.

 **ACCESS OR CORRECTIONS TO YOUR INFORMATION**

If you identify any inaccuracy in your personal information, or if you need to make a change or would like to verify such information, please contact us so that we may update your information in our records or you may go online to one of Herbalife's websites and update your own information. Our contact information is set forth below. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to accommodate all such requests.

 **COMPLAINTS**

Herbalife takes privacy concerns seriously. If you believe that Herbalife has not complied with this Privacy Policy, you may write to the address below or call us. Please describe in as much detail as possible the ways in which you believe that the Herbalife Policy has not been complied with. We will investigate your complaint promptly. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your complaint, or your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, you should contact the Office of the Chief Privacy Officer, which will serve as a liaison with Herbalife to resolve your concerns. Contact details for the Office of the Chief Privacy Officer are as follows: 310-410-9600 or [privacy@herbalife.com](mailto:privacy@herbalife.com).

 **WEBSITE SPECIFIC**

 **Protection of Children**

The Site is a general audience web site that is not specifically designed or targeted at children. We do not knowingly collect, use or disseminate any personally-identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If, however, we become aware that personally-identifiable information regarding a child under the age of 13 has been collected at the Site, we will use such information for the sole purpose of contacting a parent or guardian of the child to obtain verifiable parental consent. If we cannot obtain consent after a reasonable period of time, or if when contacted a parent or guardian requests that we do not use or maintain such information, we will make reasonable efforts to delete it from our records. Upon request by a parent or guardian, Herbalife will provide a description of the specific types of personal information collected from a child who is under the age of 13.

 **Cookies and Tracking**

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored on computer hard drives. We may use cookies to recognize you when you return to the Site in order to provide you with a better user experience. Our cookies do not contain any personally-identifying information, such as your name, or sensitive information, such as your credit card number. We may allow third parties to use cookies on the Site but we do not control the use or contents of third party cookies. Web browsers often allow you to erase existing cookies from your hard drive, block the use of cookies and/or be notified when cookies are encountered. If you elect to block cookies, please note that you may not be able to take full advantage of the features and functions of the Site. Web browsers often also allow you send a “Do Not Track” request with your browsing traffic, which would enable anonymous browsing. However, anonymous browsing would prevent Herbalife from providing you with optimal website functionality and content for the majority of our websites. For this reason, Herbalife does not honor Do Not Track requests from web browsers. However, Herbalife and our 3rd party vendors who operate on our behalf only track your browsing history for the reasons described in the Use of Information section of this Privacy Policy and we do not allow third parties to engage in online behavioral advertising on our websites.

 **Third-Party Links**

The Site may contain links to web sites operated and maintained by third parties over which we have absolutely no control. Any information you provide to third party websites will be governed under the terms of each websites' privacy policy and we encourage you to investigate and ask questions before disclosing any information to the operators of third party websites. We have no responsibility or liability whatsoever for the content, actions or policies of third party websites. The inclusion of third party websites on our Site in no way constitutes an endorsement of such websites' content, actions or policies.

 **MODIFICATIONS TO POLICY**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of March 1, 2006. Herbalife reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this Policy will be effective immediately upon notice, which may be provided to you via e-mail or by posting the latest version on our Site. Your subsequent use of the Site be deemed acceptance of such changes. Be sure to review this Privacy Policy periodically to ensure familiarity with its most current version. You can easily confirm whether any revisions have been posted since your last visit by checking the date on which the Policy was last revised, which is set forth at the bottom of this Policy. If you object to such changes, we will honor our prior privacy policies as to any data previously collected. If you disagree with the changes in our policy, however, please do not use the Site after the posting of such changes online. By using the Site following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy, you agree to all such changes.

 **CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

Residents of the State of California, under the California Civil Code, have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties, if any, to which the company has disclosed Personal Information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes (e.g., requests made in 2010 will receive information about 2009 sharing activities). We comply with this law by offering our visitors the ability to tell us not to share your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please write Herbalife at: Herbalife International of America, Inc., P.O. Box 80210, Los Angeles, CA 90080-0210 USA.

You must include this Site as the subject line, and your full name, e-mail address, and postal address in your message. Please note that any request under this Paragraph will be limited to Herbalife's use and disclosure of your personal information. You will need to make the same request of your Herbalife Independent Member if you would like to obtain information about any disclosure that he or she has made of your personal information.

 **QUESTIONS OR COMMENTS OR TO CONTACT US**

If you have questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, or you wish to access or make changes to information we have about you, please call Member Relations at 866-866-4744 (only for Members) or contact us at: 800 West Olympic Blvd., Suite 406, Los Angeles, CA 90015 or [privacy@herbalife.com](mailto:privacy@herbalife.com).

Last Revised April 7, 2014
